Alice Richardson

Lady Lake, Florida | 970-817-1904 | Alice.richardson.dev@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio | GitHub | Blog

SUMMARY

I am a **Frontend Developer** with extensive experience and a bachelor's degree in design. I have completed the Full Stack Development Immersive Program from Flatiron school. I have a keen eye for the visual aspect of user experience and a strong desire to learn and create. I firmly believe in lifelong learning, and I'm constantly exploring new ideas and technologies. Having experience in both design and development, I am confident in my ability to create the most optimal user experiences.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Bootstrap, Styled Component, Material-UI, Node, Express

GENERAL SKILLS

Figma, Photoshop, Integration with public API, Git, Github, Responsive Website, Customer Service

WORK EXPERIENCE

Zaronology Inc. | Jr. Web Application Developer

July 2021 - Present

- -Bringing mock-ups to life using HTML, CSS, Javascript.
- -Creating new features, functionality, and capabilities on the eCommerce sites.
- -Creating modular, responsive templates using modern CSS techniques and Javascript libraries.
- -Implementing a mobile-first approach to existing websites.

Food Haven Technologies Inc. | Software Engineer | Intern

May 2021- July 2021

- -Main focus Frontend building websites and apps, using **React** and React Native.
- -Testing to identify bugs and technical issues before and after deploying.
- -Maintaining an organized workflow using a project management tool (like GitHub)

Chim Media | Frontend Engineer | UX & UI Designer | Intern

Feb 2021 - May 2021

- -Design frontend webpage, integrate with public API
- -Working with in a team developing frontend, backend, and UX / UI

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

AlPrada eCommerce Web Shop// React | Material-UI | Commerce.js | Stripe| Netlify - Github | Demo Build a fully functional eCommerce application using commerce.js

- Create a shopping product page, checkout page using material-UI.
- Create functionality add, remove, update the product to the cart by using commerce.js.
- Using Stripe for card transactions and handle payment.

Greatest Pizza// React | React-hook | Styled-Component - Github | Demo

Responsive eCommerce restaurant design

- Styled frontend with React and Styled-Component.
- The website is fully responsive for a great user experience.
- Using React-hook for manipulating data and many more.

Ecofreak // Vue | Node | Express | MongoDB - Github | Demo

Web application to inspire environmentally safe practices, and learn how to lessen one's environmental footprint

- Created and styled frontend with Vue and Material design for bootstrap
- Built collaborative blog interface for users to share and contribute ideas to better help the world
- Created own API to allow users to save directly to a database

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

- Speaker at Women Who Code Boulder/Denver Monthly Meetup Video

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Jan 2020 - May 2020 | Denver, CO

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails, and JavaScript Immersive Program

Bangkok University

Feb 2011 – Apr 2014 | Bangkok, Thailand